CHRIS LANGFORD

Email: strayfrozen@yahoo.com

Address: 131 Hawkins Rd, Livingston, Tennessee 38570

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Customer-focused, adaptable, enthusiastic professional equipped with an EPA certificate and 5 years of experience as an HVAC Installation Specialist. Reliable team-player quick to grasp essential job skills and knowledge currently seeking a role in a new career field

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Aug. 2019 - Feb. 2021 Cookeville, Tennessee

Hvac Installer, Volunteer Heating and Cooling

- Test electrical circuits or components for continuity, using electrical test equipment.
- Fabricate, assemble, or install duct work or chassis parts, using portable metal-working tools or welding equipment.
- Inspect and test systems to verify system compliance with plans and specifications or to detect and locate malfunctions.

Aug. 2018 – Aug. 2019 Cookeville, Tennessee

Team Lead, Hiller Heating and Cooling

- Reassemble and test equipment following repairs.
- Lay out and connect electrical wiring between controls and equipment, according to wiring diagrams, using electrician's hand tools.
- Assemble, position and mount heating or cooling equipment, following blueprints.

Aug. 2016 – Aug. 2018 Cookeville, Tennessee

Hvac Apprentice, Integrity Heating and Cooling

- Measure, cut, thread, or bend pipe or tubing, using pipe fitter's tools.
- Study blueprints, design specifications, and manufacturers' recommendations to ascertain the configuration of heating or cooling equipment components and to ensure the proper installation of components.
- Inspect and test systems to verify system compliance with plans and specifications or to detect and locate malfunctions.

EDUCATION

May. 2017

Diploma of Completion of Hvac course: Hvac

• Tennessee College of Applied Technologies Crossville - Crossville, Tennessee

SKILLS

Electrical	Expert	Fast Learner	Expert
Mechanical	Expert	Leadership	Skillful
Troubleshooting	Expert	Computer	Skillful